<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-28T23:17:58-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Japan Series</title><subtitle>A series of memories, sights, and words describing _what_ is Japan.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kagoshima Ramen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2025/04/15/kagoshima-ramen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kagoshima Ramen" /><published>2025-04-15T08:55:01-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T08:55:01-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2025/04/15/kagoshima-ramen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2025/04/15/kagoshima-ramen.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/bd8ug5qd0tcr8z5g0amf9/kagoshima_ramen.jpeg?rlkey=3lgmzaigsaa7xc59obocw5ls9&amp;st=zj7qwqul&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="A delicious ramen with interesting company." /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>A delicious ramen with interesting company</em></p>

<p>One of my favorite things to do whenever I experience a new city in Japan is try their particular variation of ramen. This specific bowl was a variation of niboshi and tonkotsu – niboshi is a soup usually made with bonito (a type of fish) and tonkotsu is a soup made from pork.</p>

<p>Of course, the ramen was delicious… In all honesty, though, the experience eclipsed it by a wide margin.</p>

<p>When I arrived at the shop I learned that it was opening late that day. So I went to stand in line, coincidentally behind a few local high school boys who had queued up earlier than me.</p>

<p>The entire time that we waited - approximately a half-hour - we took no notice of each other. Eventually the ramen shop opened and the chef directed us to seats along the bar of his counter. Each of us gave him our orders and began to wait while the wafting smells of charred pork, fishy and porky soup, and fresh noodles filled the shop.</p>

<p>After another 15-20 minutes, the master began to serve each bowl of ramen. First, it was my seat neighbor’s turn; he is one of the high school students. The chef sat the bowl down in front of the student. I had to sneak a glance. It looked incredi–</p>

<p>Oh, my seat neighbor saw me! He looked over, smiled smugly, and nodded.</p>

<p>I should’ve mentioned this before but I don’t speak Japanese. In all likelihood, he doesn’t speak English.</p>

<p>And yet, a non-verbal message was exchanged. “Oh yeah, it looks great, doesn’t it??”</p>

<p>Soon after, I received mine. In my peripheral vision I see a movement. Ah yes, my neighbor is curious to see what I think of my own order. I returned a grin and a nod.</p>

<p>As the minutes went by with both of us slurping our soups in contentment, it was clear that we were also sharing in this fun experience.</p>

<p>The students finished their bowls a couple minutes before me. They got up to leave. Before I knew it, my neighbor stood right next to me and showed me his fist. He wanted a fist bump! I guess we became ramen pals without even saying a word.</p>

<p>The ramen was delicious, but the community experience there is what I’ll always treasure.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="restaurant" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A delicious ramen with interesting company]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fuji Speedway Chase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sports/2025/04/06/fuji-speedway-chase.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fuji Speedway Chase" /><published>2025-04-06T12:11:05-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-06T12:11:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sports/2025/04/06/fuji-speedway-chase</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sports/2025/04/06/fuji-speedway-chase.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/vwsg4bseajta20ncwuzub/fuji-speedway-chase.jpg?rlkey=0osz8zsd079ykur98507lv3ou&amp;st=ca0i5h2y&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="Two race cars chasing each other in a pre-season practice session." /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>Two race cars chasing each other in a pre-season practice session.</em></p>

<p>There is a resounding roar coming from out of view. Two cars round the final corner and turn onto the main straight at Fuji Speedway.</p>

<p>I’m a novice photographer. Iconic motorsports photos are oftentimes panning shots.</p>

<p>Panning is when the photographer stands as still as possible, sets their camera to as slow a shutter speed as they can handle, and attempt to keep their arms steady while they match the speed of the cars whizzing by. We want to capture the action as closely as we can by shooting cars with this style.</p>

<p>These two race cars are reaching nearly 300 kilometers per hour as they come into and out of view. It’s almost a miracle if you can track them from one end of your peripheral vision to the other while they pass by.</p>

<p>In this case, for a novice no less, getting a photo of the subject(s) mostly sharp against a motion blurred background is a miracle of its own.</p>

<p>I had no idea until I returned home and began editing photos that I had captured a photo with this style. This was my first time attempting this style.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two race cars chasing each other in a pre-season practice session.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Evening Train to Arita</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2025/04/01/arita-evening-train.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evening Train to Arita" /><published>2025-04-01T12:11:05-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T12:11:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2025/04/01/arita-evening-train</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2025/04/01/arita-evening-train.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/blevrndpuvnpcqd0oujfk/evening_train_to_arita.jpg?rlkey=vgt9ag3npwsmkej2zvqjg7nl6&amp;e=2&amp;st=19ddngng&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="A train on its way to Arita, Saga as the last rays of sunlight fade over the distance mountains." /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>A train on its way to Arita, Saga as the last rays of sunlight fade over the distance mountains.</em></p>

<p>Mundane and routine to some, exciting to many.</p>

<p>Arita is a town of porcelain. Its primary export is ceramic, in various shapes, styles, and sizes, for all manners of occasion.</p>

<p>Wander the streets of the town and you will find brilliant and exquisite pottery. There are art pieces. There are very standard meal plates. Water cups. Sake cups.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the town is in desperate need of visitors and shoppers. The main street of Arita Sera can stand like it is part of a movie set for a ghost town. The shops, quite empty, have passionate staff who love to show patrons around their beautiful products.</p>

<p>In some ways the town is as beautiful as a train rolling over a track in the last rays of sunset: quietly existing, with some travelers passing through… yet, lying in the beautiful countryside.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A train on its way to Arita, Saga as the last rays of sunlight fade over the distance mountains.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kochi Castle Lookout</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/06/20/kochi-castle-lookout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kochi Castle Lookout" /><published>2024-06-20T12:11:05-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-20T12:11:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/06/20/kochi-castle-lookout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/06/20/kochi-castle-lookout.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/vduubkj9c9jynpsxeichp/kochi_castle_lookout.jpg?rlkey=70fjo1t33tkmvvlwex1b4cifk&amp;st=0onob16y&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="View of Kochi from Kochi Castle, one of the few remaining original castles in Japan" /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>View of Kochi from Kochi Castle, one of the few remaining original castles in Japan</em></p>

<p>A simple view.</p>

<p>The foot of the castle has a remarkable design that has stood the test of time. Stones are layered throughout the exterior walls. They are oblong, triangular, short, large, cracked. Yet, they are still there. Records indicate many benefits but one in particular is how they allow for the passage of water; it rains frequently and in large proportions where Kochi is situated on Shikoku. If water is not allowed to pool, it is far less likely to cause erosion or deterioration.</p>

<p>Elements of construction like that are why the beautiful view from the top still exists.</p>

<p>While the image in view has changed over time, the castle remains.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[View of Kochi from Kochi Castle, one of the few remaining original castles in Japan]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tsugaru Railways Stove Train</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/03/17/tsugaru_railways_stove_train.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tsugaru Railways Stove Train" /><published>2024-03-17T22:41:18-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-17T22:41:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/03/17/tsugaru_railways_stove_train</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2024/03/17/tsugaru_railways_stove_train.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/96q7174l9po8q8j19g5sw/tsugaru_stove_train.jpg?rlkey=nhhj5h2876s6bj7oejiclokgo&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="Stove Train" /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>An old-fashioned stove train in Goshogawara, Aomori</em></p>

<p>Off-season slumber.</p>

<p>This old-fashioned train, a <em>stove train</em>, is operated by Tsugaru Railways in Aomori Prefecture only during the cold, snowy winter. What makes it a stove train? Inside this train is a coal-fired stove used to grill foods like dried squid and cuttlefish. Sadly or perhaps fortunately, this is only for the cold of winter!</p>

<p>On this particular mid-autumn day, the train sat quietly at Goshogawara Station waiting for its hibernation to be over.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An old-fashioned stove train in Goshogawara, Aomori]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monjayaki Shop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2024/03/16/monjayaki-restaurant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monjayaki Shop" /><published>2024-03-16T19:40:18-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-16T19:40:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2024/03/16/monjayaki-restaurant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/restaurant/2024/03/16/monjayaki-restaurant.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/53s8qxofe8xxwkgom9w3v/manjuyaki_storefront.jpg?rlkey=ey1gixjry4qr0oz3az82shgh9&amp;raw=1" alt="alt text" title="Storefront for a Monjayaki restaurant in Tsukishima" /></p>

<p class="image-caption"><em>A small Monjayaki shop located on Tsukishima in Tokyo</em></p>

<p>Wednesday night.</p>

<p>Everyone knows about Shibuya, Shinjuku, Shinbashi.</p>

<p>Golden Gai. Omeyoko. Omoide Yokocho.</p>

<p>These are all places that are busy with the after-work rush of salarypeople. Tourists who visit Japan see these as the popular places because they are always so busy.</p>

<p>Yet, by spending time exploring lesser-known (by foreigners) neighborhoods, such as Tsukishima, you can find these warm and breezy neighborhoods filled to the brim with conversation and metal clangs from spatulas hitting the teppanyaki to cook up Monjayaki!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="restaurant" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A small Monjayaki shop located on Tsukishima in Tokyo]]></summary></entry></feed>